ADRIENNE LEE

FRONT END DEVELOPER adriennelee.dev

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Front End Developer with 10 years experience in non-profit project management, and a background in environmental policy and engineering. My passion for finding creative solutions to untangle complicated societal problems has fuelled me in developing accessible and responsive web applications that utilize clean, dry code.

EDUCATION

Juno College of Technology - Web Development Immersive Bootcamp Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

Also: Javascript (Aug - Sept 2021) and Web Development (June - July 2021)

Ryerson University - Masters in Applied Science, Environmental Management Sept 2009 - May 2011

McMaster University - Bachelors of Science, Biochemistry Sept 2004 - May 2007

WEB DEV SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3/SCSS
- Javascript/jQuery
- React
- Git/Github
- WordPress
- Paired/Group Programming
- Accessibility Standards
- Firebase

CONTACT INFORMATION

Cell: 416-841-1232 adrienneklee@gmail.com 274 Bold Street, Hamilton, ON, L8P 1W2

EXPERIENCE

Director of Global Impact

TOURISM CARES (Sept 2018 - Oct 2021)

- Developed, designed, and iterated improvements to sustainable tourism digital training platform utilized by 2000+ professionals.
- Collaborated with 160+ travel and tech brands on corporate social responsibility and diversity, equity and inclusion strategies.
- Worked remote and cross-functionally using ASANA and Salesforce to manage global projects.
- Speaker: NY Times Travel Show 2020, TravelCon Boston, ZafigoX.
- Featured in: The Washington Post

Director of Development

G ADVENTURES | PLANETERRA (Jan 2017 - Sept 2018)

- Collaborated with Software team to develop mobile fundraising app for consumer audience.
- Team lead that worked alongside Product Management, Product Marketing, and Data Intelligence teams on communications and marketing campaigns. Utilized Trello for cross-team collaboration.
- Oversaw annual \$2M budget and planning process, increased donor revenue by 19% in one calendar year.
- Managed and mentored a team of 4.

Program and Communications Manager

G ADVENTURES | PLANETERRA (June 2012 - Dec 2016)

- Collaborated with UX team to rebrand and redesign Planeterra's website hosted on WordPress. Maintained website content.
- Wrote, proofed, and optimized monthly digital marketing and fundraising emails using MailChimp.
- Managed a portfolio of 18 programs across 10 countries that fostered livelihood diversification and market connection.
- Oversaw program budgets, contracts and requests for proposals ranging from \$5K-\$250K with risk mitigation.

FEATURED PROJECTS

Guess Who Ghibli

HTML5 | CSS3 and SCSS | Javascript | REST APIs Paired Programming

A web application made with Vanilla JS. Users are provided clues to guess randomly generated characters from the magical world of Studio Ghibli.

TBD

HTML5 and CSS3 | React | REST APIs | Firebase

TBD

TBD

HTML5 | CSS3 and SCSS | React | REST APIs Firebase | Team Programming

TBD